准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
血浓于油
编剧
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
海之霸
好啊
Yes
新发明的脚丫践踏者总算完成了
My new Tootsie Trampler is finally complete
我终于要变成踩别人的了
At last, I will be the stomper
不再是被别人踩的了
not the stompee
凯伦
Karen
救命
Help
好像来客了
I think we have company
来
Here
先把你刮下来
Let's exfoliate you
是谁啊
Who is that?
我的老天爷啊
Holy moly macarooney
儿子好
Howdy, son
妈
Ma?
爸
Pa?
凯伦  你换了新显示器吗
Karen, is that a new monitor?
你好会撩我
You charmer
别闹了  恋爱脑
Knock it off, Romeo
你们怎么会买得起这种豪华大车
How could you afford this ridiculous monstrosity?
我跟你妈中彩了
Your ma and me won the lottery
所以就搬到大城市去住了
So we moved to the big city
就跟我们高贵到不穿裤子的儿子一样
Just like our too-fancy-for-pants son
我们还特地请了管家
We got ourselves a butler
您的痰盂  女士
Your spittoon, madam?
非常好
Very good
要来参观一下豪车吗
Want a tour of the vehicle?
不太想
Not really
请进吧
Come on in
真的很高档
Real classy
很奢华吧
Purty fancy, ain't it?
得看你怎么定义很奢华
That depends on your definition of pretty and fancy
咱这新买的房车
Our new homestead on wheels
衣食住行要用的又全又好
has all the creature comforts
就比如给埃莫用的这个丝绒食槽
Like this velvet feeding trough for Elmer
它现在可以在奢侈品里打滚了
Now, he can wallow in luxury
不用滚泥巴了
instead of filth
不要  埃莫
No, Elmer
放我下来
Put me down
还有个并排茅房  适合晚上浪漫几下
And a side-by-side outhouse
for them romantical evenings
再者  空间还够给整个痞家住
Plus, there's room for the whole Plankton clan
你好啊
Howdy
你们好
Hello
那你们要过来看望多久
So how long are you visiting for?
是七  五
Seven, five
还是三分钟呢
maybe three minutes?
我们要留下来  儿子
We're here to stay, son
我们踏上了你的老路子
We're following your lead
自己开了家餐厅
and starting up our own restaurant
薯之霸
The Spud Bucket
什么鬼
What in the wha?
猜猜卖的什么菜品
Guess what's on the menu
我猜猜  土豆
Let me guess, potatoes?
原来你偷看了啊
You done peeked
我们卖土豆三明治
We got tater sandwiches
土豆蛋糕
Spud cakes
鲜榨土豆汁
Our fresh squeezed tater juice
卖给小朋友玩的土豆气球
Just for the kids, tater balloons
还有压轴好戏  土豆惊喜
And the coup de grace, Spud Surprise
克莱图斯表亲
Oh, Cousin Cletus
好
Yep
有谁说到惊喜吗
Did somebody say surprise?
我新换的显示器也就这样了
So much for my new monitor
好归好
Yeah, that's fine
但也太傻了
It's also stupid
才不会有谁愿意
No one's going to
来这种只卖土豆的餐厅吃饭
eat at a restaurant that only serves potatoes
天啊
Oh, boy
土豆
Potatoes
大家快来
Hey, everybody
这家店只卖土豆
this place sells nothing but potatoes
土豆
Potato?
街对面新开了一家土豆馆子
There's a new potato restaurant across the street
我可不会拒绝土豆
I never say no to a starchy tuber
天啊
Oh, boy
过去吃土豆吧  先生
Run to the potatoes, Sir
我要拿这个去买土豆了
I'm going to need this for spuds
大家都跑哪去了
Where's everybody going?
每道菜品都来一份
One of everything, please
一大堆土豆  皮多来一点
A bunch of potatoes, with extra peel
凯伦
Karen?
怎么了  亲爱的
Yes, dear?
大众都是白痴
People are idiots
对  亲爱的
Yes, dear
蟹堡王
别走啊  拉里
Wait, Larry
你就不要富含蛋白质的蟹黄堡吗
Wouldn't you like a nice, protein-packed Krabby Patty?
好
Yeah
抱歉  兄弟
sorry, bro
拉里得去补充碳水
but Larry needs to carbo load
怪东西
Weirdo
我最后一位客人也走了
That was me last customer
也许可以借机利用一下
Maybe I can work this to my advantage
我的餐厅
Me restaurant
上菜了
Order up
生意今天不太好吗  老螃蟹
Business a little slow today, Krabs?
那个薯之霸把我客人全吸走了
That Spud Bucket has siphoned off all me customers
我家人新开的餐厅害你停业了
My family's new restaurant has put you out of business
不如把秘方给我吧
You may as well just give me the formula
反正你也用不上了
You got no use for it now
确实
You're right
小子  过来
Boyo, come here
你赢了  痞老板
You win, Plankton
既然大家再也不想吃蟹黄堡了
Since no one wants Krabby Patties anymore
我秘方也就一文不值了
me formula is worthless
好
Yes
有这一文不值的秘方在手
With this worthless formula
我就能统治世界了
I can take over the world
那样的话
Does that
你统治世界的计划不也一文不值了吗
make your plan for world domination worthless, too?
等一下
Wait a minute
不会吧
Oh, no
凯伦  带我回家
Karen, take me home
小宝贝
Oh, muffin
笑什么  蟹老板
What's so funny, Mr. Krabs?
没什么
Nothing
我刚刚引发了一连串的事件
I just sent a series of events in motion
问题马上都可以因此解决了
that will soon solve all our problems
要怎么关掉那家破烂薯之霸
How am I going to shut down that stupid Spud Bucket?
不然就打电话找卫生检查员吧
Why don't you call the health inspector?
他每周都会关停我们
He shuts us down every week
凯伦  你可真是个天才
Karen, you're a genius
不过你是我造的  所以我是双倍天才
And since I built you, I'm a double genius
裤头村卫生局
Bikini Bottom Health Department
你看看
Just look at it
这家公共场所闹满了害虫
This joint is completely infested with vermin
而且害虫甚至还在制作食品
The vermins are even preparing the food
天啊
Oh my
这家餐厅的评级可不应该是A
This restaurant doesn't deserve an A
应该是个AAA+
It deserves a triple A plus
什么
What?
谢谢
Thank you
这才是睦邻友好
That's right neighborly
感谢先生大方资助
And thank you, sir, for your generous donation
卫生局慈善基金
to the Health Inspector Benevolent Fund
我随时都可以帮助弱势群体
Always ready to help the less fortunate
你们想要客人是吧
So you want customers, eh?
这就送你们个客人
I'll give you a customer
儿子好啊
Howdy, son
你带了什么来
What you got there?
我给你带了开店大礼  老爸
I brought you a restaurant warming present, Dad
看啊  贪吃暴客
Behold, the Insatiable Bulk
进来吧
Come on in
能吃的多得很啊
It's all you can eat
好耶
Oh, boy
我可以吃这个
I can eat this
我可以全吃了
I can eat all of this
我可以吃这个
I can eat this
我可以吃
I can eat--
我
I--
再见了  薯之霸
So long, Spud Bucket
我非谢谢你不可
Well, I just have to thank you
这位派大星
This Patrick feller
是我见过最会做土豆泥的了
is the Jim dandiest tater masher I ever did see
真见鬼
Barnacles
事情进展比我预期的还要顺利
Things are going even better than I hoped
我就爱你不择手段的样子  蟹老板
I love when you get all Machiavellian, Mr. Krabs
我有一大堆土豆要运到
I got a load of potatoes for the, uh
薯之霸
Spud Bucket
等一下
Hold on
我也有快递
I've got a delivery, too
开火
Fire in the hole
这种弹片薯条比普通薯条还要好吃
This tater shrapnel is better than Frenchy fries
你们开的垃圾薯之霸
Your awful Spud Bucket
毁了我统治世界的计划
has ruined my plans to conquer the world
这下我还能怎么办
Now what am I supposed to do?
要不你就来帮我们干活吧
Well, why don't you come work for us?
薯之霸可是家族产业
The Spud Bucket is a family business
你也是家族一份子啊  儿子
and you're family, son
要是我搞不了破坏
Well, if I can't sabotage 'em
消灭不了
annihilate 'em
也压制不住
or squelch 'em
倒不如加入得了
I might as well join 'em
一份土豆特餐
One Spud du Jour
没错  要知道
Yep, you know
做出大家都想吃的食物
cooking food that people really want to eat
其实还让我挺开心的
actually makes me pretty happy
你的土豆  先生
Your tater, sir
好啊
Oh, boy
请问一下  这个奇怪的土豆加了什么
Excuse me, what is in this peculiar potato?
那是痞式土豆
That's a Potato a la Plankton
稍微加了一小撮海霸糊增添风味
With just a pinch of chum for flavor
不会吧
Oh, no
你居然是主厨
You're the chef?
大家快放下土豆啊
Everyone, put down your potatoes
痞老板在下厨
Plankton is in the kitchen
我就不明白了
I don't get it
怎么回事
What happened?
看来我们的开的土豆馆子死得很惨
Guess our tater restaurant is a big fat failure
好吧
Well
有得必有失
You win some and you lose some
克莱图斯表亲
Cousin Cletus
请你再来一份惊喜
Another surprise, please
再见了  儿子
So long, son
我们要出发去买橄榄球队了
We're off to buy a football team
结果我的秘方还是有点价值的
Turns out me formula's worth something after all
现在谁输了呢  痞老板
Who's the loser now, Plankton?
惊喜
Surprise
有谁说到惊喜吗
Did somebody say surprise?
惊喜
Surprise
不要逗我笑
编剧
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
指导总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
礁石影院
我就爱看电影
I love going to the movies
零食
黏黏的地板让我心平气和
The sticky floors make me feel grounded
爆草花
等不及要你看这部电影了  海绵宝宝
I can't wait for you to see this movie, SpongeBob
好笑到不能再好笑了
It's the funniest thing
你这辈子我都没见过
I've never seen in your life
有这么一段情节  里面这个角色
There's this one part where this guy
来两份套餐吧
Two combos, please
戴着顶帽子
Is wearing a hat
不要剧透  派大星
No spoilers, Patrick
普鲁登斯恋爱记
"Prudence in Love"?
感觉不是很好笑
That doesn't sound funny
派大星  确定来对电影院了吗
Patrick, are you sure we're in the right theater?
我爱你  普鲁登斯
I love you, Prudence
我也是  纳撒尼尔
And I you, Nathaniel
但我更爱你  普鲁登斯
But I love you more, Prudence
那我就稍微更爱你一点  纳撒尼尔
Then I love you slightly more than that, Nathaniel
这可不兴比啊  普鲁登斯
It's not a competition, Prudence
但如果真的在比  我就快赢了
But if it were, I'd be winning
也太甜了吧
This is so sweet
但是不好笑
But it's not funny
只不过你的笑声太有感染力了
But your laughter is so infectious
就在那时  多年以来
And just then, all the years
长期的过度大笑终于付出了代价
of excessive laughing finally took their toll
海绵宝宝的爱笑骨就此卡在了高挡位
and SpongeBob's funny bone got stuck in high gear
真没那么好笑  海绵宝宝
It's not that funny, SpongeBob
你笑什么笑
What are you laughing at?
这可是情节片  不是搞笑片
This is a melodrama, not a comedy
对啊
Yes
快滚啊  爱笑的
Take a hike, Chuckles
你看这家伙有多离谱
Can you believe this guy
整场电影下来都在那样子笑
laughing all through the movie like that?
是谁那么吵
Who is making all that noise?
好了  爱笑男孩
All right, laughing boy
带着你的笑声滚出去
take your hardy har hars outside
为什么
Why can't--
为什么我笑得停不下来
why can't I stop laughing?
该怎么办
What am I going to do?
就只能
I'll just have to--
憋住
hold it in
有了
I know
憋气就行了
I'll just hold my breath
毫无疑问  先生
No doubt about it, sir
帽子
你戴着这顶帽子漂亮极了
You look fantastic in that hat
我这叫漂亮是吧
I look fantastic, huh?
别走
Wait
我没在嘲笑你
I'm not laughing at you
我真的很喜欢那顶帽子
I really like that hat
牛奶撒了你都哭
You're crying over spilled milk
[ cry over spilled milk：后悔无用 ]
抱歉
Sorry
蟹堡王
要是能赶到厨房去
OK, if I can just make it to the kitchen
就不会有谁听到我在笑了
nobody will hear me laughing
海绵宝宝  麻烦你进厨房去
SpongeBob, kindly get in the kitchen
从我的脸上下来
And off of my face
你的脸
Your face?
我脸哪好笑了
What's so funny about my face?
没什么好笑的  不关你的
Well, there's nothing funny about your--
脸
face
不要笑我
Don't laugh at me
我反倒要笑你
I laugh at you
别听他胡说
Don't listen to him
你可美了
You're beautiful
这里不会有谁听到我笑
Nobody will hear my laughs in here
我还要吃东西呢
I'm eating here
这家餐厅为什么在笑我
Why is the restaurant laughing at us?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
你的笑声恶作剧
Your little laughing prank
把我客人全吓跑了
just scared away all the customers
解释清楚  小子
Explain yourself, boyo
他在笑我的脸  蟹老板
He's laughing at my face, Mr. Krabs
我没在笑你  章鱼哥
I'm not laughing at you, Squidward
我什么都没笑
I'm not laughing at anything
蟹老板  怎么办
Mr. Krabs, what do I do?
想点别的什么好事  别笑了
Think of happy thoughts and just knock it off
冒犯到我了
I am offended
没人来接我菲菲的单
There is no one here to take my Fifi's order
千分万分对不起  上流小姐
Gold-plated sorries, Lady Upturn
章鱼哥先生
Mr. Squidward
马上就会给你接贵宾专用订单
will take your very important order right away
我需要救护车
I need an ambulance
我遭遇了不幸  你竟然还敢笑
How dare you laugh at my misfortune
蟹老板  马上解雇这个白痴
Mr. Krabs, fire this cretin at once
听到了吧
You heard her
等你啥时候不笑不犯傻了再回来
Come back when you're not a giggling idiot
不准回来
Don't come back?
可是蟹老板  我不是故意要笑的
But, Mr. Krabs, I'm not laughing on purpose
他在嘲笑你  菲菲
He's laughing at you, Fifi
对不起  菲菲
I'm sorry, Fifi
我是个怪物
I'm a monster
得躲起来
I got to hide
那样我的笑声就不会伤及无辜了
That way, my laughter won't hurt anyone else
非常好
OK, good
一片黑
It's dark
看不到东西就没得笑了
If there's nothing to see, there's nothing to laugh at
对吧
Right?
今天要对机器人动手术
Today, we will be operating on a robot
机器人
Robot
太刺激了
How exciting
接下来会怎么做呢
What will they think of next?
我先开始拧松第一颗螺栓
I will begin by loosening the first bolt
护士  扳手
Nurse, wrench
还挺紧的
This is really on tight
护士  海绵
Nurse, sponge
手术室里禁止大笑
Laughing is not allowed in the operating room
给我出去
Get out of here
我是医生了
I am the surgeon now
迷人
Fascinating
急诊
不好笑
That is not funny
通缉
爱笑疯子
墓地
The cemetery
墓地里面没什么好笑的
There's nothing funny in a cemetery
还是就在这里度过余生好了
Maybe I'll just live the rest of my life here
小丑
Clowns?
完了
Oh, no
世上有两种小丑
There are two kinds of clowns in this world
皮笑肉不笑的小丑
clowns that are only laughing on the outside
以及肉笑皮不笑的小丑
and clowns that are only laughing on the inside
闪鼻小丑皮笑肉也笑
Sparkle Nose the Clown was both
因此成为了明星
and that's what made him a star
好庄重
So solemn
得回避一下
I should leave
天啊  我坐在尸体上面
Holy herring, I'm squatting on a corpse
能不能别坐我胸口
Would you get off my chest?
你还活着
You're alive?
我当然还活着了
Of course, I'm alive
这可是生前葬礼  全让你搞砸了
This is a living funeral, and you're ruining it
[ 生前葬礼：在世时为自己举办的葬礼 ]
抱歉
Sorry
我没在笑你  闪鼻
I'm not laughing at you, Sparkle Nose
我这就从你胸口上下去
I'll just get off of your chest
我对花环上的花粉过敏
I'm allergic to wreath pollen
快逃啊  他要爆炸了
Cheese it, he's going to blow
抱歉
Sorry
你把我的小丑葬礼变成了笑话
You turned my clown funeral into a joke
原谅我  闪鼻
Forgive me, Sparkle Nose
禁止游荡
几小时后  可怜的海绵宝宝
Hours later, poor SpongeBob
依然笑得停不下来
still could not stop laughing
他的嘴笑到合不拢  张得特别大
And his laughing mouth got so big
占满了一整张脸
it took over his whole face
我都已经笑累了
I'm tired of all this cackling and chuckling
真的好想
I feel more like I want to--
七大洋影院  正在放映
悲泣  最悲伤的电影
悲泣
"Weep"?
最悲伤的电影
"The saddest movie ever"
有了
That's it
一开始是电影害我笑的
A movie started my laughing
再看一部应该就不会再笑了
Maybe a movie can stop it
抱歉
I'm sorry
我忍不住
I can't hold it
奶奶
Grandma?
你也笑得停不下来
You can't stop laughing either?
那当然了  宝贝孙子
Of course not, dearie
我的爱笑骨好多年前就卡住了
My funny bone got stuck years ago
那时我跟你一样大
when I was your age
你的爱笑骨
Your funny bone?
没错
That's right
我们全家都会这样
It happens to everyone in our family
你要为自己的笑声自豪  海绵宝宝
Be proud of that laugh, SpongeBob
海绵家就应该要笑对生活
To be a SquarePants is to laugh loud at life
跟我一起哈哈大笑吧
Enjoy a good laugh with me
谢了  奶奶
Thanks, Grandma
这种悲情电影总能逗得我笑
These tearjerker movies always crack me up
我爆米花吃光了
I'm all out of popcorn
这下悲剧了
Now it's a tragedy